<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <records>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Conference Proceedings"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Guilherme, Vitor
          </author>
          <author>
            Vincenzi, Auri
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>An initial investigation of ChatGPT unit test generation capability</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <pages>15-24</pages>
      <isbn>9798400716294</isbn>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1145&#x2F;3624032.3624035</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Context: Software testing ensures software quality, but developers often disregard it. The use of automated testing generation is pursued to reduce the consequences of overlooked test cases in a software project. Problem: In the context of Java programs, several tools can completely automate generating unit test sets. Additionally, studies are conducted to offer evidence regarding the quality of the generated test sets. However, it is worth noting that these tools rely on machine learning and other AI algorithms rather than incorporating the latest advancements in Large Language Models (LLMs). Solution: This work aims to evaluate the quality of Java unit tests generated by an OpenAI LLM algorithm, using metrics like code coverage and mutation test score. Method: For this study, 33 programs used by other researchers in the field of automated test generation were selected. This approach was employed to establish a baseline for comparison purposes. For each program, 33 unit test sets were generated automatically, without human interference, by changing Open AI API parameters. After executing each test set, metrics such as code line coverage, mutation score, and success rate of test execution were collected to evaluate the efficiency and effectiveness of each set. Summary of Results: Our findings revealed that the OpenAI LLM test set demonstrated similar performance across all evaluated aspects compared to traditional automated Java test generation tools used in the previous research. These results are particularly remarkable considering the simplicity of the experiment and the fact that the generated test code did not undergo human analysis.</abstract>
      <publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>ACM International Conference Proceeding Series</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>automated test generation</keyword>
        <keyword>coverage testing</keyword>
        <keyword>experimental software engineering</keyword>
        <keyword>mutation testing</keyword>
        <keyword>software testing</keyword>
        <keyword>testing tools</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Conference Proceedings"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Hemmati, Hadi
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>How Effective Are Code Coverage Criteria?</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2015</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <pages>151-156</pages>
      <isbn>9781467379892</isbn>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1109&#x2F;QRS.2015.30</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Code coverage is one of the main metrics to measure the adequacy of a test case&#x2F;suite. It has been studied a lot in academia and used even more in industry. However, a test case may cover a piece of code (no matter what coverage metric is being used) but miss its faults. In this paper, we studied several existing and standard control and data flow coverage criteria on a set of developer-written fault-revealing test cases from several releases of five open source projects. We found that a) basic criteria such as statement coverage is very weak (detecting only 10% of the faults), b) combining several control-flow coverage together is better than the strongest criterion alone (28% vs. 19%), c) a basic data-flow coverage can detect many undetected faults (79% of the undetected faults by control-flow coverage can be detected by a basic def&#x2F;use pair coverage), and d) on average 15% of the faults may not be detected by any of the standard control and data-flow coverage criteria. Classification of the undetected faults showed that they are mostly to do with specification (missing logic).</abstract>
      <publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers Inc.</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Proceedings - 2015 IEEE International Conference on Software Quality, Reliability and Security, QRS 2015</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>Code Coverage</keyword>
        <keyword>Control Flow</keyword>
        <keyword>Data Flow</keyword>
        <keyword>Effectiveness</keyword>
        <keyword>Experiment</keyword>
        <keyword>Fault Categorization</keyword>
        <keyword>Software Testing</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Conference Proceedings"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Bhatia, Shreya
          </author>
          <author>
            Gandhi, Tarushi
          </author>
          <author>
            Kumar, Dhruv
          </author>
          <author>
            Jalote, Pankaj
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Unit Test Generation using Generative AI : A Comparative Performance Analysis of Autogeneration Tools</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <pages>54-61</pages>
      <isbn>9798400705793</isbn>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1145&#x2F;3643795.3648396</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Generating unit tests is a crucial task in software development, demanding substantial time and effort from programmers. The advent of Large Language Models (LLMs) introduces a novel avenue for unit test script generation. This research aims to experimentally investigate the effectiveness of LLMs, specifically exemplified by ChatGPT, for generating unit test scripts for Python programs, and how the generated test cases compare with those generated by an existing unit test generator (Pynguin). For experiments, we consider three types of code units: 1) Procedural scripts, 2) Function-based modular code, and 3) Class-based code. The generated test cases are evaluated based on criteria such as coverage, correctness, and readability. Our results show that ChatGPT&#39;s performance is comparable with Pynguin in terms of coverage, though for some cases its performance is superior to Pynguin. We also find that about a third of assertions generated by ChatGPT for some categories were incorrect. Our results also show that there is minimal overlap in missed statements between ChatGPT and Pynguin, thus, suggesting that a combination of both tools may enhance unit test generation performance. Finally, in our experiments, prompt engineering improved ChatGPT&#39;s performance, achieving a much higher coverage.∗These authors contributed equally.</abstract>
      <publisher>Association for Computing Machinery, Inc</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Proceedings - 2024 International Workshop on Large Language Models for Code, LLM4Code 2024</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>ChatGPT</keyword>
        <keyword>generative AI</keyword>
        <keyword>large language models</keyword>
        <keyword>unit test generation</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Zapkus, Dovydas Marius
          </author>
          <author>
            Slotkienė, Asta
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Unit Test Generation Using Large Language Models: A Systematic Literature Review</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>5</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <pages>136-144</pages>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.15388&#x2F;lmitt.2024.20</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Unit testing is a fundamental aspect of software development, ensuring the correctness and robustness of code implementations. Traditionally, unit tests are manually crafted by developers based on their understanding of the code and its requirements. However, this process can be time-consuming, errorprone, and may overlook certain edge cases. In recent years, there has been growing interest in leveraging large language models (LLMs) for automating the generation of unit tests. LLMs, such as GPT (Generative Pre-trained Transformer), CodeT5, StarCoder, LLaMA, have demonstrated remarkable capabilities in natural language understanding and code generation tasks. By using LLMs, researchers aim to develop techniques that automatically generate unit tests from code snippets or specifications, thus optimizing the software testing process. This paper presents a literature review of articles that use LLMs for unit test generation tasks. It also discusses the history of the most commonly used large language models and their parameters, including the first time they have been used for code generation tasks. The result of this study presents the large language models for code and unit test generation tasks and their increasing popularity in code generation domain, indicating a great promise for the future of unit test generation using LLMs.</abstract>
      <publisher>Vilnius University Press</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Vilnius University Open Series</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Mathews, Noble Saji
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Code Generation and Testing in the Era of AI-Native Software Engineering</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
      </dates>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Bick, Alexander
          </author>
          <author>
            Blandin, Adam
          </author>
          <author>
            Deming, David J
          </author>
          <author>
            Louis, St
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>The Rapid Adoption of Generative AI One Federal Reserve Bank Plaza</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Generative artificial intelligence (AI) is a potentially important new technology, but its impact on the economy depends on the speed and intensity of adoption. This paper reports results from a series of nationally representative U.S. surveys of generative AI use at work and at home. As of late 2024, nearly 40 percent of the U.S. population age 18-64 uses generative AI. 23 percent of employed respondents had used generative AI for work at least once in the previous week, and 9 percent used it every work day. Relative to each technology&#39;s first mass-market product launch, work adoption of generative AI has been as fast as the personal computer (PC), and overall adoption has been faster than either PCs or the internet. Generative AI and PCs have very similar early adoption patterns by education, occupation, and other characteristics. Between 1 and 5 percent of all work hours are currently assisted by generative AI, and respondents report time savings equivalent to 1.4 percent of total work hours. This suggests that substantial productivity gains from generative AI are possible.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nber.org&#x2F;data-appendix&#x2F;w32966</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kaddour, Jean
          </author>
          <author>
            Harris, Joshua
          </author>
          <author>
            Mozes, Maximilian
          </author>
          <author>
            Bradley, Herbie
          </author>
          <author>
            Raileanu, Roberta
          </author>
          <author>
            McHardy, Robert
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Challenges and Applications of Large Language Models</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Large Language Models (LLMs) went from non-existent to ubiquitous in the machine learning discourse within a few years. Due to the fast pace of the field, it is difficult to identify the remaining challenges and already fruitful application areas. In this paper, we aim to establish a systematic set of open problems and application successes so that ML researchers can comprehend the field&#39;s current state more quickly and become productive.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2307.10169</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kumar, Pranjal
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Large language models (LLMs): survey, technical frameworks, and future challenges</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>9</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <volume>57</volume>
      <issue>9</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1007&#x2F;s10462-024-10888-y</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Artificial intelligence (AI) has significantly impacted various fields. Large language models (LLMs) like GPT-4, BARD, PaLM, Megatron-Turing NLG, Jurassic-1 Jumbo etc., have contributed to our understanding and application of AI in these domains, along with natural language processing (NLP) techniques. This work provides a comprehensive overview of LLMs in the context of language modeling, word embeddings, and deep learning. It examines the application of LLMs in diverse fields including text generation, vision-language models, personalized learning, biomedicine, and code generation. The paper offers a detailed introduction and background on LLMs, facilitating a clear understanding of their fundamental ideas and concepts. Key language modeling architectures are also discussed, alongside a survey of recent works employing LLM methods for various downstream tasks across different domains. Additionally, it assesses the limitations of current approaches and highlights the need for new methodologies and potential directions for significant advancements in this field.</abstract>
      <publisher>Springer Nature</publisher>
      <periodical><full-title>Artificial Intelligence Review</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
        <keyword>Artificial intelligence</keyword>
        <keyword>Generative language models</keyword>
        <keyword>Large language models</keyword>
        <keyword>Machine learning</keyword>
        <keyword>Natural language processing</keyword>
        <keyword>Neural networks</keyword>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>114-the-art-of-software-testing-3-edition</title>
      </titles>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Schäfer, Max
          </author>
          <author>
            Nadi, Sarah
          </author>
          <author>
            Eghbali, Aryaz
          </author>
          <author>
            Tip, Frank
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>An Empirical Evaluation of Using Large Language Models for Automated Unit Test Generation</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>12</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Unit tests play a key role in ensuring the correctness of software. However, manually creating unit tests is a laborious task, motivating the need for automation. Large Language Models (LLMs) have recently been applied to this problem, utilizing additional training or few-shot learning on examples of existing tests. This paper presents a large-scale empirical evaluation on the effectiveness of LLMs for automated unit test generation without additional training or manual effort, providing the LLM with the signature and implementation of the function under test, along with usage examples extracted from documentation. We also attempt to repair failed generated tests by re-prompting the model with the failing test and error message. We implement our approach in TestPilot, a test generation tool for JavaScript that automatically generates unit tests for all API functions in an npm package. We evaluate TestPilot using OpenAI&#39;s gpt3.5-turbo LLM on 25 npm packages with a total of 1,684 API functions. The generated tests achieve a median statement coverage of 70.2% and branch coverage of 52.8%, significantly improving on Nessie, a recent feedback-directed JavaScript test generation technique, which achieves only 51.3% statement coverage and 25.6% branch coverage. We also find that 92.8% of TestPilot&#39;s generated tests have no more than 50% similarity with existing tests (as measured by normalized edit distance), with none of them being exact copies. Finally, we run TestPilot with two additional LLMs, OpenAI&#39;s older code-cushman-002 LLM and the open LLM StarCoder. Overall, we observed similar results with the former (68.2% median statement coverage), and somewhat worse results with the latter (54.0% median statement coverage), suggesting that the effectiveness of the approach is influenced by the size and training set of the LLM, but does not fundamentally depend on the specific model.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2302.06527</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Book"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Beck, Kent.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Test-driven development : by example</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>20062003</year>
      </dates>
      <pages>220</pages>
      <isbn>0321146530</isbn>
      <publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Vaswani, Ashish
          </author>
          <author>
            Brain, Google
          </author>
          <author>
            Shazeer, Noam
          </author>
          <author>
            Parmar, Niki
          </author>
          <author>
            Uszkoreit, Jakob
          </author>
          <author>
            Jones, Llion
          </author>
          <author>
            Gomez, Aidan N
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaiser, Łukasz
          </author>
          <author>
            Polosukhin, Illia
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Attention Is All You Need</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
      </dates>
      <isbn>1706.03762v7</isbn>
      <abstract>The dominant sequence transduction models are based on complex recurrent or convolutional neural networks that include an encoder and a decoder. The best performing models also connect the encoder and decoder through an attention mechanism. We propose a new simple network architecture, the Transformer, based solely on attention mechanisms, dispensing with recurrence and convolutions entirely. Experiments on two machine translation tasks show these models to be superior in quality while being more parallelizable and requiring significantly less time to train. Our model achieves 28.4 BLEU on the WMT 2014 English-to-German translation task, improving over the existing best results, including ensembles, by over 2 BLEU. On the WMT 2014 English-to-French translation task, our model establishes a new single-model state-of-the-art BLEU score of 41.8 after training for 3.5 days on eight GPUs, a small fraction of the training costs of the best models from the literature. We show that the Transformer generalizes well to other tasks by applying it successfully to English constituency parsing both with large and limited training data. * Equal contribution. Listing order is random. Jakob proposed replacing RNNs with self-attention and started the effort to evaluate this idea. Ashish, with Illia, designed and implemented the first Transformer models and has been crucially involved in every aspect of this work. Noam proposed scaled dot-product attention, multi-head attention and the parameter-free position representation and became the other person involved in nearly every detail. Niki designed, implemented, tuned and evaluated countless model variants in our original codebase and tensor2tensor. Llion also experimented with novel model variants, was responsible for our initial codebase, and efficient inference and visualizations. Lukasz and Aidan spent countless long days designing various parts of and implementing tensor2tensor, replacing our earlier codebase, greatly improving results and massively accelerating our research. † Work performed while at Google Brain.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Openai, Alec Radford
          </author>
          <author>
            Openai, Karthik Narasimhan
          </author>
          <author>
            Openai, Tim Salimans
          </author>
          <author>
            Openai, Ilya Sutskever
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Improving Language Understanding by Generative Pre-Training</title>
      </titles>
      <abstract>Natural language understanding comprises a wide range of diverse tasks such as textual entailment, question answering, semantic similarity assessment, and document classification. Although large unlabeled text corpora are abundant, labeled data for learning these specific tasks is scarce, making it challenging for discriminatively trained models to perform adequately. We demonstrate that large gains on these tasks can be realized by generative pre-training of a language model on a diverse corpus of unlabeled text, followed by discriminative fine-tuning on each specific task. In contrast to previous approaches, we make use of task-aware input transformations during fine-tuning to achieve effective transfer while requiring minimal changes to the model architecture. We demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach on a wide range of benchmarks for natural language understanding. Our general task-agnostic model outperforms discriminatively trained models that use architectures specifically crafted for each task, significantly improving upon the state of the art in 9 out of the 12 tasks studied. For instance, we achieve absolute improvements of 8.9% on commonsense reasoning (Stories Cloze Test), 5.7% on question answering (RACE), and 1.5% on textual entailment (MultiNLI).</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gluebenchmark.com&#x2F;leaderboard</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Radford, Alec
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Jeffrey
          </author>
          <author>
            Child, Rewon
          </author>
          <author>
            Luan, David
          </author>
          <author>
            Amodei, Dario
          </author>
          <author>
            Sutskever, Ilya
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Language Models are Unsupervised Multitask Learners</title>
      </titles>
      <abstract>Natural language processing tasks, such as question answering, machine translation, reading comprehension , and summarization, are typically approached with supervised learning on task-specific datasets. We demonstrate that language models begin to learn these tasks without any explicit supervision when trained on a new dataset of millions of webpages called WebText. When conditioned on a document plus questions, the answers generated by the language model reach 55 F1 on the CoQA dataset-matching or exceeding the performance of 3 out of 4 baseline systems without using the 127,000+ training examples. The capacity of the language model is essential to the success of zero-shot task transfer and increasing it improves performance in a log-linear fashion across tasks. Our largest model, GPT-2, is a 1.5B parameter Transformer that achieves state of the art results on 7 out of 8 tested language modeling datasets in a zero-shot setting but still underfits WebText. Samples from the model reflect these improvements and contain coherent paragraphs of text. These findings suggest a promising path towards building language processing systems which learn to perform tasks from their naturally occurring demonstrations.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;codelucas&#x2F;newspaper</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Kaplan, Jared
          </author>
          <author>
            McCandlish, Sam
          </author>
          <author>
            Henighan, Tom
          </author>
          <author>
            Brown, Tom B.
          </author>
          <author>
            Chess, Benjamin
          </author>
          <author>
            Child, Rewon
          </author>
          <author>
            Gray, Scott
          </author>
          <author>
            Radford, Alec
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Jeffrey
          </author>
          <author>
            Amodei, Dario
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Scaling Laws for Neural Language Models</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2020</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>1</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>We study empirical scaling laws for language model performance on the cross-entropy loss. The loss scales as a power-law with model size, dataset size, and the amount of compute used for training, with some trends spanning more than seven orders of magnitude. Other architectural details such as network width or depth have minimal effects within a wide range. Simple equations govern the dependence of overfitting on model&#x2F;dataset size and the dependence of training speed on model size. These relationships allow us to determine the optimal allocation of a fixed compute budget. Larger models are significantly more sample-efficient, such that optimally compute-efficient training involves training very large models on a relatively modest amount of data and stopping significantly before convergence.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2001.08361</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Hoffmann, Jordan
          </author>
          <author>
            Borgeaud, Sebastian
          </author>
          <author>
            Mensch, Arthur
          </author>
          <author>
            Buchatskaya, Elena
          </author>
          <author>
            Cai, Trevor
          </author>
          <author>
            Rutherford, Eliza
          </author>
          <author>
            Casas, Diego de Las
          </author>
          <author>
            Hendricks, Lisa Anne
          </author>
          <author>
            Welbl, Johannes
          </author>
          <author>
            Clark, Aidan
          </author>
          <author>
            Hennigan, Tom
          </author>
          <author>
            Noland, Eric
          </author>
          <author>
            Millican, Katie
          </author>
          <author>
            Driessche, George van den
          </author>
          <author>
            Damoc, Bogdan
          </author>
          <author>
            Guy, Aurelia
          </author>
          <author>
            Osindero, Simon
          </author>
          <author>
            Simonyan, Karen
          </author>
          <author>
            Elsen, Erich
          </author>
          <author>
            Rae, Jack W.
          </author>
          <author>
            Vinyals, Oriol
          </author>
          <author>
            Sifre, Laurent
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Training Compute-Optimal Large Language Models</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>3</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>We investigate the optimal model size and number of tokens for training a transformer language model under a given compute budget. We find that current large language models are significantly undertrained, a consequence of the recent focus on scaling language models whilst keeping the amount of training data constant. By training over 400 language models ranging from 70 million to over 16 billion parameters on 5 to 500 billion tokens, we find that for compute-optimal training, the model size and the number of training tokens should be scaled equally: for every doubling of model size the number of training tokens should also be doubled. We test this hypothesis by training a predicted compute-optimal model, Chinchilla, that uses the same compute budget as Gopher but with 70B parameters and 4$\times$ more more data. Chinchilla uniformly and significantly outperforms Gopher (280B), GPT-3 (175B), Jurassic-1 (178B), and Megatron-Turing NLG (530B) on a large range of downstream evaluation tasks. This also means that Chinchilla uses substantially less compute for fine-tuning and inference, greatly facilitating downstream usage. As a highlight, Chinchilla reaches a state-of-the-art average accuracy of 67.5% on the MMLU benchmark, greater than a 7% improvement over Gopher.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2203.15556</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Brown, Tom B.
          </author>
          <author>
            Mann, Benjamin
          </author>
          <author>
            Ryder, Nick
          </author>
          <author>
            Subbiah, Melanie
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaplan, Jared
          </author>
          <author>
            Dhariwal, Prafulla
          </author>
          <author>
            Neelakantan, Arvind
          </author>
          <author>
            Shyam, Pranav
          </author>
          <author>
            Sastry, Girish
          </author>
          <author>
            Askell, Amanda
          </author>
          <author>
            Agarwal, Sandhini
          </author>
          <author>
            Herbert-Voss, Ariel
          </author>
          <author>
            Krueger, Gretchen
          </author>
          <author>
            Henighan, Tom
          </author>
          <author>
            Child, Rewon
          </author>
          <author>
            Ramesh, Aditya
          </author>
          <author>
            Ziegler, Daniel M.
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Jeffrey
          </author>
          <author>
            Winter, Clemens
          </author>
          <author>
            Hesse, Christopher
          </author>
          <author>
            Chen, Mark
          </author>
          <author>
            Sigler, Eric
          </author>
          <author>
            Litwin, Mateusz
          </author>
          <author>
            Gray, Scott
          </author>
          <author>
            Chess, Benjamin
          </author>
          <author>
            Clark, Jack
          </author>
          <author>
            Berner, Christopher
          </author>
          <author>
            McCandlish, Sam
          </author>
          <author>
            Radford, Alec
          </author>
          <author>
            Sutskever, Ilya
          </author>
          <author>
            Amodei, Dario
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Language Models are Few-Shot Learners</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2020</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Recent work has demonstrated substantial gains on many NLP tasks and benchmarks by pre-training on a large corpus of text followed by fine-tuning on a specific task. While typically task-agnostic in architecture, this method still requires task-specific fine-tuning datasets of thousands or tens of thousands of examples. By contrast, humans can generally perform a new language task from only a few examples or from simple instructions - something which current NLP systems still largely struggle to do. Here we show that scaling up language models greatly improves task-agnostic, few-shot performance, sometimes even reaching competitiveness with prior state-of-the-art fine-tuning approaches. Specifically, we train GPT-3, an autoregressive language model with 175 billion parameters, 10x more than any previous non-sparse language model, and test its performance in the few-shot setting. For all tasks, GPT-3 is applied without any gradient updates or fine-tuning, with tasks and few-shot demonstrations specified purely via text interaction with the model. GPT-3 achieves strong performance on many NLP datasets, including translation, question-answering, and cloze tasks, as well as several tasks that require on-the-fly reasoning or domain adaptation, such as unscrambling words, using a novel word in a sentence, or performing 3-digit arithmetic. At the same time, we also identify some datasets where GPT-3&#39;s few-shot learning still struggles, as well as some datasets where GPT-3 faces methodological issues related to training on large web corpora. Finally, we find that GPT-3 can generate samples of news articles which human evaluators have difficulty distinguishing from articles written by humans. We discuss broader societal impacts of this finding and of GPT-3 in general.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2005.14165</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Ouyang, Long
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Jeff
          </author>
          <author>
            Jiang, Xu
          </author>
          <author>
            Almeida, Diogo
          </author>
          <author>
            Wainwright, Carroll L
          </author>
          <author>
            Mishkin, Pamela
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang Sandhini Agarwal Katarina Slama Alex Ray John Schulman Jacob Hilton Fraser Kelton Luke Miller Maddie Simens Amanda Askell, Chong
          </author>
          <author>
            Welinder Paul Christiano, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            Leike, Jan
          </author>
          <author>
            Lowe, Ryan
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Training language models to follow instructions with human feedback</title>
      </titles>
      <isbn>2203.02155v1</isbn>
      <abstract>Making language models bigger does not inherently make them better at following a user&#39;s intent. For example, large language models can generate outputs that are untruthful, toxic, or simply not helpful to the user. In other words, these models are not aligned with their users. In this paper, we show an avenue for aligning language models with user intent on a wide range of tasks by fine-tuning with human feedback. Starting with a set of labeler-written prompts and prompts submitted through the OpenAI API, we collect a dataset of labeler demonstrations of the desired model behavior, which we use to fine-tune GPT-3 using supervised learning. We then collect a dataset of rankings of model outputs, which we use to further fine-tune this supervised model using reinforcement learning from human feedback. We call the resulting models InstructGPT. In human evaluations on our prompt distribution, outputs from the 1.3B parameter InstructGPT model are preferred to outputs from the 175B GPT-3, despite having 100x fewer parameters. Moreover, InstructGPT models show improvements in truthfulness and reductions in toxic output generation while having minimal performance regressions on public NLP datasets. Even though InstructGPT still makes simple mistakes, our results show that fine-tuning with human feedback is a promising direction for aligning language models with human intent.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Touvron, Hugo
          </author>
          <author>
            Lavril, Thibaut
          </author>
          <author>
            Izacard, Gautier
          </author>
          <author>
            Martinet, Xavier
          </author>
          <author>
            Lachaux, Marie-Anne
          </author>
          <author>
            Lacroix, Timothée
          </author>
          <author>
            Rozière, Baptiste
          </author>
          <author>
            Goyal, Naman
          </author>
          <author>
            Hambro, Eric
          </author>
          <author>
            Azhar, Faisal
          </author>
          <author>
            Rodriguez, Aurelien
          </author>
          <author>
            Joulin, Armand
          </author>
          <author>
            Grave, Edouard
          </author>
          <author>
            Lample, Guillaume
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>LLaMA: Open and Efficient Foundation Language Models</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>2</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>We introduce LLaMA, a collection of foundation language models ranging from 7B to 65B parameters. We train our models on trillions of tokens, and show that it is possible to train state-of-the-art models using publicly available datasets exclusively, without resorting to proprietary and inaccessible datasets. In particular, LLaMA-13B outperforms GPT-3 (175B) on most benchmarks, and LLaMA-65B is competitive with the best models, Chinchilla-70B and PaLM-540B. We release all our models to the research community.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2302.13971</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Rafailov, Rafael
          </author>
          <author>
            Sharma, Archit
          </author>
          <author>
            Mitchell, Eric
          </author>
          <author>
            Ermon, Stefano
          </author>
          <author>
            Manning, Christopher D.
          </author>
          <author>
            Finn, Chelsea
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Direct Preference Optimization: Your Language Model is Secretly a Reward Model</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>While large-scale unsupervised language models (LMs) learn broad world knowledge and some reasoning skills, achieving precise control of their behavior is difficult due to the completely unsupervised nature of their training. Existing methods for gaining such steerability collect human labels of the relative quality of model generations and fine-tune the unsupervised LM to align with these preferences, often with reinforcement learning from human feedback (RLHF). However, RLHF is a complex and often unstable procedure, first fitting a reward model that reflects the human preferences, and then fine-tuning the large unsupervised LM using reinforcement learning to maximize this estimated reward without drifting too far from the original model. In this paper we introduce a new parameterization of the reward model in RLHF that enables extraction of the corresponding optimal policy in closed form, allowing us to solve the standard RLHF problem with only a simple classification loss. The resulting algorithm, which we call Direct Preference Optimization (DPO), is stable, performant, and computationally lightweight, eliminating the need for sampling from the LM during fine-tuning or performing significant hyperparameter tuning. Our experiments show that DPO can fine-tune LMs to align with human preferences as well as or better than existing methods. Notably, fine-tuning with DPO exceeds PPO-based RLHF in ability to control sentiment of generations, and matches or improves response quality in summarization and single-turn dialogue while being substantially simpler to implement and train.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2305.18290</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Minaee, Shervin
          </author>
          <author>
            Mikolov, Tomas
          </author>
          <author>
            Nikzad, Narjes
          </author>
          <author>
            Chenaghlu, Meysam
          </author>
          <author>
            Socher, Richard
          </author>
          <author>
            Amatriain, Xavier
          </author>
          <author>
            Gao, Jianfeng
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Large Language Models: A Survey</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2025</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>3</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Large Language Models (LLMs) have drawn a lot of attention due to their strong performance on a wide range of natural language tasks, since the release of ChatGPT in November 2022. LLMs&#39; ability of general-purpose language understanding and generation is acquired by training billions of model&#39;s parameters on massive amounts of text data, as predicted by scaling laws \cite{kaplan2020scaling,hoffmann2022training}. The research area of LLMs, while very recent, is evolving rapidly in many different ways. In this paper, we review some of the most prominent LLMs, including three popular LLM families (GPT, LLaMA, PaLM), and discuss their characteristics, contributions and limitations. We also give an overview of techniques developed to build, and augment LLMs. We then survey popular datasets prepared for LLM training, fine-tuning, and evaluation, review widely used LLM evaluation metrics, and compare the performance of several popular LLMs on a set of representative benchmarks. Finally, we conclude the paper by discussing open challenges and future research directions.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2402.06196</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Chen, Mark
          </author>
          <author>
            Tworek, Jerry
          </author>
          <author>
            Jun, Heewoo
          </author>
          <author>
            Yuan, Qiming
          </author>
          <author>
            Pinto, Henrique Ponde de Oliveira
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaplan, Jared
          </author>
          <author>
            Edwards, Harri
          </author>
          <author>
            Burda, Yuri
          </author>
          <author>
            Joseph, Nicholas
          </author>
          <author>
            Brockman, Greg
          </author>
          <author>
            Ray, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Puri, Raul
          </author>
          <author>
            Krueger, Gretchen
          </author>
          <author>
            Petrov, Michael
          </author>
          <author>
            Khlaaf, Heidy
          </author>
          <author>
            Sastry, Girish
          </author>
          <author>
            Mishkin, Pamela
          </author>
          <author>
            Chan, Brooke
          </author>
          <author>
            Gray, Scott
          </author>
          <author>
            Ryder, Nick
          </author>
          <author>
            Pavlov, Mikhail
          </author>
          <author>
            Power, Alethea
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaiser, Lukasz
          </author>
          <author>
            Bavarian, Mohammad
          </author>
          <author>
            Winter, Clemens
          </author>
          <author>
            Tillet, Philippe
          </author>
          <author>
            Such, Felipe Petroski
          </author>
          <author>
            Cummings, Dave
          </author>
          <author>
            Plappert, Matthias
          </author>
          <author>
            Chantzis, Fotios
          </author>
          <author>
            Barnes, Elizabeth
          </author>
          <author>
            Herbert-Voss, Ariel
          </author>
          <author>
            Guss, William Hebgen
          </author>
          <author>
            Nichol, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Paino, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Tezak, Nikolas
          </author>
          <author>
            Tang, Jie
          </author>
          <author>
            Babuschkin, Igor
          </author>
          <author>
            Balaji, Suchir
          </author>
          <author>
            Jain, Shantanu
          </author>
          <author>
            Saunders, William
          </author>
          <author>
            Hesse, Christopher
          </author>
          <author>
            Carr, Andrew N.
          </author>
          <author>
            Leike, Jan
          </author>
          <author>
            Achiam, Josh
          </author>
          <author>
            Misra, Vedant
          </author>
          <author>
            Morikawa, Evan
          </author>
          <author>
            Radford, Alec
          </author>
          <author>
            Knight, Matthew
          </author>
          <author>
            Brundage, Miles
          </author>
          <author>
            Murati, Mira
          </author>
          <author>
            Mayer, Katie
          </author>
          <author>
            Welinder, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            McGrew, Bob
          </author>
          <author>
            Amodei, Dario
          </author>
          <author>
            McCandlish, Sam
          </author>
          <author>
            Sutskever, Ilya
          </author>
          <author>
            Zaremba, Wojciech
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Evaluating Large Language Models Trained on Code</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2021</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>We introduce Codex, a GPT language model fine-tuned on publicly available code from GitHub, and study its Python code-writing capabilities. A distinct production version of Codex powers GitHub Copilot. On HumanEval, a new evaluation set we release to measure functional correctness for synthesizing programs from docstrings, our model solves 28.8% of the problems, while GPT-3 solves 0% and GPT-J solves 11.4%. Furthermore, we find that repeated sampling from the model is a surprisingly effective strategy for producing working solutions to difficult prompts. Using this method, we solve 70.2% of our problems with 100 samples per problem. Careful investigation of our model reveals its limitations, including difficulty with docstrings describing long chains of operations and with binding operations to variables. Finally, we discuss the potential broader impacts of deploying powerful code generation technologies, covering safety, security, and economics.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2107.03374</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Jimenez, Carlos E.
          </author>
          <author>
            Yang, John
          </author>
          <author>
            Wettig, Alexander
          </author>
          <author>
            Yao, Shunyu
          </author>
          <author>
            Pei, Kexin
          </author>
          <author>
            Press, Ofir
          </author>
          <author>
            Narasimhan, Karthik
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>SWE-bench: Can Language Models Resolve Real-World GitHub Issues?</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Language models have outpaced our ability to evaluate them effectively, but for their future development it is essential to study the frontier of their capabilities. We find real-world software engineering to be a rich, sustainable, and challenging testbed for evaluating the next generation of language models. To this end, we introduce SWE-bench, an evaluation framework consisting of $2,294$ software engineering problems drawn from real GitHub issues and corresponding pull requests across $12$ popular Python repositories. Given a codebase along with a description of an issue to be resolved, a language model is tasked with editing the codebase to address the issue. Resolving issues in SWE-bench frequently requires understanding and coordinating changes across multiple functions, classes, and even files simultaneously, calling for models to interact with execution environments, process extremely long contexts and perform complex reasoning that goes far beyond traditional code generation tasks. Our evaluations show that both state-of-the-art proprietary models and our fine-tuned model SWE-Llama can resolve only the simplest issues. The best-performing model, Claude 2, is able to solve a mere $1.96$% of the issues. Advances on SWE-bench represent steps towards LMs that are more practical, intelligent, and autonomous.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2310.06770</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Le, Hung
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Yue
          </author>
          <author>
            Gotmare, Akhilesh Deepak
          </author>
          <author>
            Savarese, Silvio
          </author>
          <author>
            Hoi, Steven C. H.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>CodeRL: Mastering Code Generation through Pretrained Models and Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Program synthesis or code generation aims to generate a program that satisfies a problem specification. Recent approaches using large-scale pretrained language models (LMs) have shown promising results, yet they have some critical limitations. In particular, they often follow a standard supervised fine-tuning procedure to train a code generation model only from the pairs of natural-language problem descriptions and ground-truth programs. Such paradigm largely ignores some important but potentially useful signals in the problem specification such as unit tests, which thus often results in poor performance when solving complex unseen coding tasks. To address the limitations, we propose &quot;CodeRL&quot;, a new framework for program synthesis tasks through pretrained LMs and deep reinforcement learning (RL). Specifically, during training, we treat the code-generating LM as an actor network, and introduce a critic network that is trained to predict the functional correctness of generated programs and provide dense feedback signals to the actor. During inference, we introduce a new generation procedure with a critical sampling strategy that allows a model to automatically regenerate programs based on feedback from example unit tests and critic scores. For the model backbones, we extended the encoder-decoder architecture of CodeT5 with enhanced learning objectives, larger model sizes, and better pretraining data. Our method not only achieves new SOTA results on the challenging APPS benchmark, but also shows strong zero-shot transfer capability with new SOTA results on the simpler MBPP benchmark.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2207.01780</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Chen, Xinyun
          </author>
          <author>
            Lin, Maxwell
          </author>
          <author>
            Schärli, Nathanael
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhou, Denny
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Teaching Large Language Models to Self-Debug</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>10</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Large language models (LLMs) have achieved impressive performance on code generation. However, for complex programming tasks, generating the correct solution in one go becomes challenging, thus some prior works have designed program repair approaches to improve code generation performance. In this work, we propose Self-Debugging, which teaches a large language model to debug its predicted program via few-shot demonstrations. In particular, we demonstrate that Self-Debugging can teach the large language model to perform rubber duck debugging; i.e., without any human feedback on the code correctness or error messages, the model is able to identify its mistakes by investigating the execution results and explaining the generated code in natural language. Self-Debugging achieves the state-of-the-art performance on several code generation benchmarks, including the Spider dataset for text-to-SQL generation, TransCoder for C++-to-Python translation, and MBPP for text-to-Python generation. On the Spider benchmark where there are no unit tests to verify the correctness of predictions, Self-Debugging with code explanation consistently improves the baseline by 2-3%, and improves the prediction accuracy on problems of the hardest level by 9%. On TransCoder and MBPP where unit tests are available, Self-Debugging improves the baseline accuracy by up to 12%. Meanwhile, by leveraging feedback messages and reusing failed predictions, Self-Debugging notably improves sample efficiency, and can match or outperform baseline models that generate more than 10x candidate programs.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2304.05128</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Chen, Bei
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Fengji
          </author>
          <author>
            Nguyen, Anh
          </author>
          <author>
            Zan, Daoguang
          </author>
          <author>
            Lin, Zeqi
          </author>
          <author>
            Lou, Jian-Guang
          </author>
          <author>
            Chen, Weizhu
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>CodeT: Code Generation with Generated Tests</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>11</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>The task of generating code solutions for a given programming problem can benefit from the use of pre-trained language models such as Codex, which can produce multiple diverse samples. However, a major challenge for this task is to select the most appropriate solution from the multiple samples generated by the pre-trained language models. A natural way to evaluate the quality and correctness of a code solution is to run it against a set of test cases, but the manual creation of such test cases is often costly and time-consuming. In this paper, we propose a novel method, CodeT, that leverages the same pre-trained language models to automatically generate test cases for the code samples, thus reducing the human effort and increasing the coverage of the test scenarios. CodeT then executes the code samples using the generated test cases, and performs a dual execution agreement, which considers both the consistency of the outputs against the generated test cases and the agreement of the outputs with other code samples. We conduct comprehensive experiments on four benchmarks, HumanEval, MBPP, APPS and CodeContests, using five different pre-trained language models with varying sizes and capabilities. Our results show that CodeT can significantly improve the performance of code solution selection over previous methods, achieving remarkable and consistent gains across different models and benchmarks. For instance, CodeT improves the pass@1 metric on HumanEval to 65.8%, which represents an absolute improvement of 18.8% over the code-davinci-002 model, and an absolute improvement of more than 20% over the previous state-of-the-art results.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2207.10397</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Chen, Mark
          </author>
          <author>
            Tworek, Jerry
          </author>
          <author>
            Jun, Heewoo
          </author>
          <author>
            Yuan, Qiming
          </author>
          <author>
            Pinto, Henrique Ponde de Oliveira
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaplan, Jared
          </author>
          <author>
            Edwards, Harri
          </author>
          <author>
            Burda, Yuri
          </author>
          <author>
            Joseph, Nicholas
          </author>
          <author>
            Brockman, Greg
          </author>
          <author>
            Ray, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Puri, Raul
          </author>
          <author>
            Krueger, Gretchen
          </author>
          <author>
            Petrov, Michael
          </author>
          <author>
            Khlaaf, Heidy
          </author>
          <author>
            Sastry, Girish
          </author>
          <author>
            Mishkin, Pamela
          </author>
          <author>
            Chan, Brooke
          </author>
          <author>
            Gray, Scott
          </author>
          <author>
            Ryder, Nick
          </author>
          <author>
            Pavlov, Mikhail
          </author>
          <author>
            Power, Alethea
          </author>
          <author>
            Kaiser, Lukasz
          </author>
          <author>
            Bavarian, Mohammad
          </author>
          <author>
            Winter, Clemens
          </author>
          <author>
            Tillet, Philippe
          </author>
          <author>
            Such, Felipe Petroski
          </author>
          <author>
            Cummings, Dave
          </author>
          <author>
            Plappert, Matthias
          </author>
          <author>
            Chantzis, Fotios
          </author>
          <author>
            Barnes, Elizabeth
          </author>
          <author>
            Herbert-Voss, Ariel
          </author>
          <author>
            Guss, William Hebgen
          </author>
          <author>
            Nichol, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Paino, Alex
          </author>
          <author>
            Tezak, Nikolas
          </author>
          <author>
            Tang, Jie
          </author>
          <author>
            Babuschkin, Igor
          </author>
          <author>
            Balaji, Suchir
          </author>
          <author>
            Jain, Shantanu
          </author>
          <author>
            Saunders, William
          </author>
          <author>
            Hesse, Christopher
          </author>
          <author>
            Carr, Andrew N.
          </author>
          <author>
            Leike, Jan
          </author>
          <author>
            Achiam, Josh
          </author>
          <author>
            Misra, Vedant
          </author>
          <author>
            Morikawa, Evan
          </author>
          <author>
            Radford, Alec
          </author>
          <author>
            Knight, Matthew
          </author>
          <author>
            Brundage, Miles
          </author>
          <author>
            Murati, Mira
          </author>
          <author>
            Mayer, Katie
          </author>
          <author>
            Welinder, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            McGrew, Bob
          </author>
          <author>
            Amodei, Dario
          </author>
          <author>
            McCandlish, Sam
          </author>
          <author>
            Sutskever, Ilya
          </author>
          <author>
            Zaremba, Wojciech
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Evaluating Large Language Models Trained on Code</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2021</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>We introduce Codex, a GPT language model fine-tuned on publicly available code from GitHub, and study its Python code-writing capabilities. A distinct production version of Codex powers GitHub Copilot. On HumanEval, a new evaluation set we release to measure functional correctness for synthesizing programs from docstrings, our model solves 28.8% of the problems, while GPT-3 solves 0% and GPT-J solves 11.4%. Furthermore, we find that repeated sampling from the model is a surprisingly effective strategy for producing working solutions to difficult prompts. Using this method, we solve 70.2% of our problems with 100 samples per problem. Careful investigation of our model reveals its limitations, including difficulty with docstrings describing long chains of operations and with binding operations to variables. Finally, we discuss the potential broader impacts of deploying powerful code generation technologies, covering safety, security, and economics.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2107.03374</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Ji, Ziwei
          </author>
          <author>
            Lee, Nayeon
          </author>
          <author>
            Frieske, Rita
          </author>
          <author>
            Yu, Tiezheng
          </author>
          <author>
            Su, Dan
          </author>
          <author>
            Xu, Yan
          </author>
          <author>
            Ishii, Etsuko
          </author>
          <author>
            Bang, Yejin
          </author>
          <author>
            Chen, Delong
          </author>
          <author>
            Dai, Wenliang
          </author>
          <author>
            Chan, Ho Shu
          </author>
          <author>
            Madotto, Andrea
          </author>
          <author>
            Fung, Pascale
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Survey of Hallucination in Natural Language Generation</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2024</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>7</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1145&#x2F;3571730</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Natural Language Generation (NLG) has improved exponentially in recent years thanks to the development of sequence-to-sequence deep learning technologies such as Transformer-based language models. This advancement has led to more fluent and coherent NLG, leading to improved development in downstream tasks such as abstractive summarization, dialogue generation and data-to-text generation. However, it is also apparent that deep learning based generation is prone to hallucinate unintended text, which degrades the system performance and fails to meet user expectations in many real-world scenarios. To address this issue, many studies have been presented in measuring and mitigating hallucinated texts, but these have never been reviewed in a comprehensive manner before. In this survey, we thus provide a broad overview of the research progress and challenges in the hallucination problem in NLG. The survey is organized into two parts: (1) a general overview of metrics, mitigation methods, and future directions; (2) an overview of task-specific research progress on hallucinations in the following downstream tasks, namely abstractive summarization, dialogue generation, generative question answering, data-to-text generation, machine translation, and visual-language generation; and (3) hallucinations in large language models (LLMs). This survey serves to facilitate collaborative efforts among researchers in tackling the challenge of hallucinated texts in NLG.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2202.03629</url>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;dx.doi.org&#x2F;10.1145&#x2F;3571730</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Report"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Ouyang, Long
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Jeff
          </author>
          <author>
            Jiang, Xu
          </author>
          <author>
            Almeida, Diogo
          </author>
          <author>
            Wainwright, Carroll L
          </author>
          <author>
            Mishkin, Pamela
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang Sandhini Agarwal Katarina Slama Alex Ray John Schulman Jacob Hilton Fraser Kelton Luke Miller Maddie Simens Amanda Askell, Chong
          </author>
          <author>
            Welinder Paul Christiano, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            Leike, Jan
          </author>
          <author>
            Lowe, Ryan
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Training language models to follow instructions with human feedback</title>
      </titles>
      <isbn>2203.02155v1</isbn>
      <abstract>Making language models bigger does not inherently make them better at following a user&#39;s intent. For example, large language models can generate outputs that are untruthful, toxic, or simply not helpful to the user. In other words, these models are not aligned with their users. In this paper, we show an avenue for aligning language models with user intent on a wide range of tasks by fine-tuning with human feedback. Starting with a set of labeler-written prompts and prompts submitted through the OpenAI API, we collect a dataset of labeler demonstrations of the desired model behavior, which we use to fine-tune GPT-3 using supervised learning. We then collect a dataset of rankings of model outputs, which we use to further fine-tune this supervised model using reinforcement learning from human feedback. We call the resulting models InstructGPT. In human evaluations on our prompt distribution, outputs from the 1.3B parameter InstructGPT model are preferred to outputs from the 175B GPT-3, despite having 100x fewer parameters. Moreover, InstructGPT models show improvements in truthfulness and reductions in toxic output generation while having minimal performance regressions on public NLP datasets. Even though InstructGPT still makes simple mistakes, our results show that fine-tuning with human feedback is a promising direction for aligning language models with human intent.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Liang, Percy
          </author>
          <author>
            Bommasani, Rishi
          </author>
          <author>
            Lee, Tony
          </author>
          <author>
            Tsipras, Dimitris
          </author>
          <author>
            Soylu, Dilara
          </author>
          <author>
            Yasunaga, Michihiro
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Yian
          </author>
          <author>
            Narayanan, Deepak
          </author>
          <author>
            Wu, Yuhuai
          </author>
          <author>
            Kumar, Ananya
          </author>
          <author>
            Newman, Benjamin
          </author>
          <author>
            Yuan, Binhang
          </author>
          <author>
            Yan, Bobby
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Ce
          </author>
          <author>
            Cosgrove, Christian
          </author>
          <author>
            Manning, Christopher D.
          </author>
          <author>
            Ré, Christopher
          </author>
          <author>
            Acosta-Navas, Diana
          </author>
          <author>
            Hudson, Drew A.
          </author>
          <author>
            Zelikman, Eric
          </author>
          <author>
            Durmus, Esin
          </author>
          <author>
            Ladhak, Faisal
          </author>
          <author>
            Rong, Frieda
          </author>
          <author>
            Ren, Hongyu
          </author>
          <author>
            Yao, Huaxiu
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, Jue
          </author>
          <author>
            Santhanam, Keshav
          </author>
          <author>
            Orr, Laurel
          </author>
          <author>
            Zheng, Lucia
          </author>
          <author>
            Yuksekgonul, Mert
          </author>
          <author>
            Suzgun, Mirac
          </author>
          <author>
            Kim, Nathan
          </author>
          <author>
            Guha, Neel
          </author>
          <author>
            Chatterji, Niladri
          </author>
          <author>
            Khattab, Omar
          </author>
          <author>
            Henderson, Peter
          </author>
          <author>
            Huang, Qian
          </author>
          <author>
            Chi, Ryan
          </author>
          <author>
            Xie, Sang Michael
          </author>
          <author>
            Santurkar, Shibani
          </author>
          <author>
            Ganguli, Surya
          </author>
          <author>
            Hashimoto, Tatsunori
          </author>
          <author>
            Icard, Thomas
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Tianyi
          </author>
          <author>
            Chaudhary, Vishrav
          </author>
          <author>
            Wang, William
          </author>
          <author>
            Li, Xuechen
          </author>
          <author>
            Mai, Yifan
          </author>
          <author>
            Zhang, Yuhui
          </author>
          <author>
            Koreeda, Yuta
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Holistic Evaluation of Language Models</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2023</year>
          <pub-dates>
            <date>10</date>
          </pub-dates>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Language models (LMs) are becoming the foundation for almost all major language technologies, but their capabilities, limitations, and risks are not well understood. We present Holistic Evaluation of Language Models (HELM) to improve the transparency of language models. First, we taxonomize the vast space of potential scenarios (i.e. use cases) and metrics (i.e. desiderata) that are of interest for LMs. Then we select a broad subset based on coverage and feasibility, noting what&#39;s missing or underrepresented (e.g. question answering for neglected English dialects, metrics for trustworthiness). Second, we adopt a multi-metric approach: We measure 7 metrics (accuracy, calibration, robustness, fairness, bias, toxicity, and efficiency) for each of 16 core scenarios when possible (87.5% of the time). This ensures metrics beyond accuracy don&#39;t fall to the wayside, and that trade-offs are clearly exposed. We also perform 7 targeted evaluations, based on 26 targeted scenarios, to analyze specific aspects (e.g. reasoning, disinformation). Third, we conduct a large-scale evaluation of 30 prominent language models (spanning open, limited-access, and closed models) on all 42 scenarios, 21 of which were not previously used in mainstream LM evaluation. Prior to HELM, models on average were evaluated on just 17.9% of the core HELM scenarios, with some prominent models not sharing a single scenario in common. We improve this to 96.0%: now all 30 models have been densely benchmarked on the same core scenarios and metrics under standardized conditions. Our evaluation surfaces 25 top-level findings. For full transparency, we release all raw model prompts and completions publicly for further analysis, as well as a general modular toolkit. We intend for HELM to be a living benchmark for the community, continuously updated with new scenarios, metrics, and models.</abstract>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
          <url>http:&#x2F;&#x2F;arxiv.org&#x2F;abs&#x2F;2211.09110</url>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
  </records>
</xml>